PERSONAL INFORMATION

Luca Giuseppe Borrelli



- Via Schiaparelli, Milan (Italy)
- +39 342 090 53 63
- in www.linkedin.com/in/lucaborrelli
- S Luca Borrelli

Sex Male | Nationality Italian

ABOUT ME

10 years of experience in software industry.

I worked in Sales, Marketing and as a Junior IT consultant. Knowledge on positioning and drive business growth for ERP, CRM, Mobility, Cloud Technology (SaaS, IaaS, PaaS), Cyber Security (es: IAM, SIEM, etc.), Big Data, Analytics, BI and Data Center software solutions.

Knowledge of SMB and LE Italian Market – and knowledge of Service Providers, Systems Integrators, Indipendent Software Vendors and Italian IT ecosystem.

Happy to provide guidance and support on sales/marketing projects, best practices and business benefits.

WORK EXPERIENCE

October 2016 -Present

Key Account Manager @ Beta Systems Software



Bollate (MI - Italy), Via IV Novembre 92

Bets Systems is specialized in Midlleware, Cyber Security (Es: IAM; SIEM, etc.) and IT Automation. We work on IBM ecosystem.I am focusing on:

- Key Account Management: business plan and execution on key account for customer growth on existing and new opportunities;
- Marketing support: support of marketing headquarter on new strategic project marketing implementation and execution, in alignment with Sales Director, for lead generation (es: direct and content marketing, with external vendors, etc.)
- Participation of fair and events for new opportunities and support brand awareness.
- Channel Development: support on development on strategic alliances for business growth with channel sales managers.
- Weekly Forecast on Sales Director and daily CRM management on business opportunities pipeline.

January 2016 – October 2016

Technical Field Account Manager @ EON Consulting



EON Consulting - Como (Italy), Via Mariano Tentorio 14

EON is software house and system integrator specialized in ERP, CRM and Analytics solutions. INFOR Partner (INFOR is the 3rd worldwide vendor in ERP market).

February 2014 – December 2015

Business Development Specialist SMB @ SAP



SAP - Barcelona, Carrer De Josep Pla 2

Cloud solutions for Mid-Market. Hybrid position between sales and marketing. Marketing Campaign preparation and execution to generate new leads and pipeline generation for business growth. In particular:

- Direct Marketing: mail campaign preparation and execution.
- Webinar & Field Marketing: online webinar preparation, and execution & field event support with marketing managers, sales manager and presales;
- Marketing call to execute marketing campaigns and generate new business opportunities and nurture existing busines opportunities for business growth, aligned with account managers and Sales Director.

April 2013 – November 2013

Junior IT Consultant @ SYDEMA



Sydema S.r.I., Via Privata Turro 6 Milan (Italy)

SYDEMA is a software house specialized in the developing and implementation of solution software for Banks and Financial Institutions.

I worked as a Junior IT Consultant and business analyst in different projects on banks for BPER Banking group customer.

EDUCATION

September 2006 – October 2011

Economics and Law, Master's Degree

Università Cattolica del Sacro Cuore, Milan (Italy)

September 2002 – July 2006

Scientific Technological College

Liceo scientifico tecnologico Leonardo da Vinci, Carate Brianza (Milan, Italy)

I also acquired a (basic/medium) knowledge of Computer science and programming (es: Phyton, etc.).

PERSONAL SKILLS

Mother tongue

Italian

Other languages

English

Fluent in written and spoken

French and Spanish

Intermediate

Computer skills

Excellent command of:

- Microsoft Word;
- Power Point (Very High professional dynamic company's presentations);
- Excel (very high professional);
- Outlook;
- Programming language: Phyton (intermediate), HTML, CSS;
- CRM: Salesforce, SAP, Hubspot, Sugar, etc.,
- Marketing Platform: Adobe, BuzzSumo, MailChimp Campaign Monitor, etc.)

Sales and Marketing Certification

Linkedin Professional, Social Media Selling at SAP (Sap), Writing Emails to Get Results (Sap), Overcoming Objections, Present Complex Information, Managing Customer Expectations, Win-win negotiation (Dale Carnergie – Training).

Further information

I like playing football with friends. I played football in different teams for many years.

I like travelling and volunteering in many social causes.